

Toronto, Canada Permanent Resident in Canada

GitHub | LinkedIn | Google Scholar duckhai.le@mail.utoronto.ca | (+1) 437 249 2462

Research Statement

My research is not limited to a single topic but rather spans most aspects of AI, e.g. speech recognition, natural language processing, computer vision, time-series analysis, large language models, multi-modality, data-centric AI, and semi-supervised learning. Most of my works focused on practical applications that serve business needs.

I'm an AI researcher with a business mindset. My ultimate goal is to commercialize research, providing affordable medical care for everyone.

Education

University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada

Master of Applied Science in Biomedical Engineering

January 2024 - Present

- - The university was ranked 1st in Canada, 9th in the world in AI (QS Rankings)
 - Research area: Machine Learning for Multivariate Time-series
 - Supervisor: Prof. Shehroz Khan (h-index 26)

RWTH Aachen University

Aachen, Germany

Bachelor Thesis in Computer Science

December 2022

- The university was ranked 2nd in Germany and 50th in the world in Computer Science (THE Rankings)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Hermann Ney (h-index 113), Prof. Ralf Schlüter (h-index 50)
- Thesis title: Unsupervised Pre-Training for Vietnamese Automatic Speech Recognition in the HYKIST Project [DOI]
- Thesis grade: 1.0/6.0 (German grade), 100/100 (International percentage)

FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

Jülich, Germany

Bachelor in Biomedical Engineering, taught-in-German program

December 2022

- The university was ranked 1st among Universities of Applied Sciences in Germany in Engineering and Informatics (WiWo Ranking)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Ilya Digel (h-index 23)
- Overall grade: 2.2/6.0 (German grade), 80/100 (International percentage)

Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

October 2016

Bachelor in International Economic Relations

- The university was ranked 1st overall in Vietnam and 701-750th in the world (QS Rankings)
- Top 100 out of 354897 candidates (0.02%) with total scores of 27/30 in the Vietnamese National High School Graduation Examination 2015 in Mathematics, Physics and English
- Grade: 1st ranked Valedictorian

Industry Experience

FPT Software AI Center, FPT Corporation

Remote

AI Researcher

· Co-leader of 20 AI residents, engineers and PhD students, together with Prof. Truong Son Hy

• Research project: Research and Product Development of Multimodal Multilingual Large Language Models

Research Experience

University Health Network

Toronto, Canada

March 2024 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2024 – Present

- University Health Network is ranked as the world's 5th best hospital (Newsweek 2023) and ranked 1st in rehabilitation.
- Research project: Predicting Agitation in People Living with Dementia

Machine Learning and Human Language Technology Group, RWTH Aachen University

Aachen, Germany

Student Research Assistant

May 2021 - Present

- Research supervisor: Prof. Hermann Ney (h-index 113, 63000+ citations, the most cited researcher and the highest h-index in the world in Speech Recognition and in Machine Translation)
- Research co-supervisor: Prof. Ralf Schlüter (h-index 50, 12000+ citations)
- Research topic: Semi-Supervised Learning for Medical Domain Speech Recognition

FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

Geilenkirchen, Germany

Research Intern

January 2016 - March 2016

- Research labs: Freshman Laboratory of Electrical Engineering, Laboratory of Molecular Medicine and Cell, Biophysics Lab, Chemistry Laboratory, and Freshman Biomedical Labor
- Received certificates for contribution

(*) Equal contribution

Under anonymized period: Preprints are privately available in GitHub repo

7. A Wearable Device Dataset for Mental Health Assessment Using Laser Doppler Flowmetry and Fluorescence Spectroscopy Sensors

Khai Le-Duc*, Tan-Hanh Pham*, Minh Ngoc Nguyen*, Trang Nguyen, Quang Minh Luu, Ba Kien Tran, Truong-Son Hy, Viktor Dremin, Sergei Sokolovsky, Edik Rafailov

Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024, 63 pages

6. Domain-Shift in Medical Machine Translation

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy, Shehroz Khan Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024

5. Dynamic Intermediate Loss for Fine-tuning Self-Supervised Models

Khai Le-Duc, Christoph Lüscher, Ralf Schlüter

Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024

Preprint

4. Medical Spoken Named Entity Recognition

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, David Thulke, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Ralf Schlüter Preprint comes soon, overall 3-3-3-3/5 at ACL 2024 (A*-ranked conference)

Peer-reviewed

3. Real-time Speech Summarization for Medical Conversations

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>*, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen*, Long Vo-Dang, Truong-Son Hy Interspeech 2024 (A-ranked Conference by CORE, #1 Conference in Speech Processing)

2. VietMed: A Dataset and Benchmark for Automatic Speech Recognition of Vietnamese in the Medical Domain Khai Le-Duc

LREC-COLING 2024 (A-ranked Joint Conference by CORE, acceptance rate 52%), 27 pages

1. Development of Hybrid ASR Systems for Low Resource Medical Domain Conversational Telephone Speech Christoph Lüscher, Mohammad Zeineldeen, Zijian Yang, Peter Vieting, <u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, Weiyue Wang, Ralf Schlüter, Hermann Nev

ITG Speech Communication 2023 (#5 ASR Conference by Research.com)

Awards & Honors

SGS Research Travel Grant University of Toronto (950 CAD for LREC-COLING 2024 - the highest amount ever)	2024
ORT Conference Participation Award University Health Network (500 CAD for LREC-COLING 2024)	2024
Top 12 HackerRank in Germany HackerRank - the largest competitive programming platform in the world	2020
Valedictorian Scholarship of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City	2015

Selected Open-Source Projects

Demo for Multilingual Speech Translation

- The first free-of-charge medical speech translation API in the world, being deployed on cloud in German medical centers to support conversations between German doctors and international patients without language barriers
- Co-contributor of the demo

Awesome Competitive Programming Problems

- Curated extensive library of Python data structures and algorithms specifically designed for competitive programming contests
- Solved various problems including String Manipulation, Graph Theory, Greedy, Dynamic Programming, Sliding Window, Mathematics and Recursion
- On GitHub top 1 trending, received 170+ stars

Mathnasium

Instructor - Part time

October 2023 - November 2023

Toronto, Canada

- Communicated with students in an understandable way about daily lessons
 - · Developed automated teaching tools and methods to help students learn mathematics

Techniker Krankenkasse

March 2016 - June 2016

Geilenkirchen, Germany

Volunteer - Full time

- The company is Germany's largest health insurance fund
- Maintained business contacts with 1000+ student customers, organized and executed 3 events to advertise company's insurance packages, and created marketing concepts
- · Received certificate for contribution

Technical Skills

Programming skills:

- Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, Java (basic)
- Databases (basic): Snowflake, SQL, MongoDB
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Fairseq, HuggingFace
- Data Science Libraries: NumPy, SciKit-Learn, Pandas, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Data Analysis and Statistical Tools (basic): SPSS, Excel
- Image Processing Libraries: OpenCV, scikit-image
- · Operating Systems: Linux, Git
- Document Preparation: LaTeX, Markdown

<u>Relevant courseworks</u>: Medical Statistics, Information Processing, Image Processing, Medical Computer Science, Introducing MATLAB, Introducing to Python.

Spoken languages: Vietnamese (Native), English (IELTS 7.0), German (C1)